Finding Aid for the W. A. Harper Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
W. A. HARPER PAPERS
Undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0191
.42 linear feet
A BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
1880 - Born.
1932-1942 - Professor of Religious Education at Vanderbilt School of Religion.
Denomination: Church
Denomination: Christian Church
Degrees Held: M.A., D.D., LL.D.
Author and Teacher.
May 11, 1942 - Died.
- Description of Series
  - Correspondence - Outging. 137 letters, carbon copies. Letters deal with Debt of Honor Campaign. Arranged chronologically. Covers period from September 23, 1937-Jan. 28, 1939. F 1-13. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Incoming - 65 letters; 10 postcards; 1 telegram. Arranged alphabetically. F14-20. (Box 1)
  - Articles by Harper. 37 items, holograph, typescript, and carbon copies. Arranged alphabetically by title. F 21-35. (Box 1)
  - Published Articles by Harper. Arranged alphabetically by title. 5 articles. F 36-38. (Box 1)
  - Business papers and Holograph notes. F 39. (Box 1)
  - Information about the Debt of Honor Campaign. F 40-41. (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets and Articles by Others. Two booklets and one article. "Echoes from Washington" by Mrs. W. A. Harper; Abstracts of Selected Graduate Theses in Religious Education 1935; The New Program of Christian Leadership Education. F 42-43. (Box 1)
    Location: M/3/28
- LIST OF INCOMING CORRESPONDENTS
  - Atwater, Bertha (1), May 2, 1938
  - Brown, Charles (1), Nov. 26, 1937
  - Copp, Belton A. (1), Dec. 14, 1937
  - Davenport, J. W. (2), Jan. 18, 1938; Feb. 15, 1938
  - DeJarnette; A. L. (3), Jan. 17, 1938; Feb. 18, 1938; May 28, 1938
  - Denison, Warren (1), April 25, 1938
  - Dollar, C. Carl (2), Dec. 3, 1937; Jan. 19, 1938
  - Evans, D. Ellis (1), April 14, 1938
  - Fogle, Oscar M. (1), Feb. 10, 1938
  - G-?, R. W. (1), March 24, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Gilroy, William E. (1), Feb. 24, 1938
  - Hurst, Alfred W. (6), Jan. 6, 1938; postmarked Jan. 20, 1938; postmarked Feb. 25, 1933; April 4, 1938; April 18, 1938; April 30, 1938
  - Keith, William A. (1), Feb. 17, 1938
  - Krueger, E. T. (1), April 6, 1938
  - Metcalf, Mrs. H. G. (1), April 16, 1938
  - Nightingale, Abram (4), Jan. 23, 1938; Jan. 26, 1938; April 13, 1938; May 1, 1938
  - Ramseur, Vernon B. (14), Dec. 4, 1937; Feb. 1, 1938; Feb. 9, 1938; March 3, 1938; March 4, 1938; March 7, 1938; March 11, 1938; March 18, 1938; March 22, 1938 - 2; March 28, 1938; April 15, 1938
  - Richards, G. B. (3), Jan. 24, 1939; April 5, 1939; April 14, 1939
  - Rucks, A. R. (2), April 7, 1938; April 21, 1938
  - Sees, John V. (1), n.d.
  - Sherwood, Carlton M. (6), Oct. 2, 1937 - telegram; Oct. 19, 1937; Jan. 19, 1938; Jan. 12, 1938; Jan. 28, 1938; Sept. 21, 1937
  - Steinwart, George F. (1), March 19, 1938
  - Sweet, M. J. (10), postmarked Jan. 9, 1938; Jan. 11, 1938; Feb. 2, 1938; Feb. 16, 1938; April 1, 1938; April 19, 1938; April 25, 1938; May 2, 1938; May 24, 1938; May 26, 1938
  - Vandersall, Stanley B. (1), April 29, 1938
  - White, Edwin (7), Feb. 4, 1938; Feb. 10, 1938; Feb. 17, 1938; Feb. 23, 1938; March 1, 1938; March 19, 1938; May 31, 1938
  - Wingfield, Marshall (4), Dec. 5, 1937; Jan. 26, 1938; Feb. 17, 1938; April 5, 1938
- List of Articles
  "Altering Attitudes" - F 21
  "The American College i n Turkey" - F 21
  "Are College Students to Blame" - 4 copies; 1 partial copy. F 22-23.
  "The Bible i n Religious Education" - 2 copies. F 24
  "Can Civilization Be Saved" - F24.
  " Christian Culture in the College Program" - F 25.
  "Foreword" - F 25
  "An Educationally Defensive Program of Religious Education" - 2 copies F 26.
  "The Form of the Curriculum" - 2 copies. F 27
  "Historic Chapters in Christian Education in America," review by Harper - F 27.
  "Industry and Character" - F 28
  "Let Us Pray" - F 28
  "The Negro Christians of the South" - F 28
  "A New Technique for Teaching Religion" - F 29
  "Patriotism i n Southern Finance" - F 29
  "A Prophet in Religious Education - Horace Bushnell" - F 29
  "Publishing Houses and the Curriculum of Religious Education" - 2 copies - F 30
  "The Religion of Business" - 2 copies - F 31
  "Religious Education in the Seminary" - F 32
  "Rethinking Missions at the Home Base - 2 copies - F 32
  "The Supervision of Religious Education" - F 33
  "The Teaching of Religion in the American College" - F 33
  "Teaching Through Life - 2 copies - F 34
  "Toward Experience - Centered Leadership Education" - F 34
  "Trends and Forces Affecting Student life" - F 35
  "Values and Character" - F35
  "What Shall Be Our Attitude Toward Alcohol?" - F 35
- List of Published Articles
  "The American College in Turkey" - F 36
  "Can Preaching Be Saved?" - F 37
  "An Educationally Defensive Program of Religious Education" - F 37
  "The Field of Religion" - 2 copies - F 38
  "A National Experiment in Character Building" - F 38